in.gov 2001-04-09

# accessIndiana Privacy Policy

|  ****

**_accessIndiana_ Privacy Policy **

Thank you for visiting the _accessIndiana_ Web site and reviewing our privacy policy. The information we receive depends on what you do when you visit our site. The essence of our privacy policy is simple and clear: we will collect **no** personal information about you when you visit our web site unless you voluntarily choose to provide that information to us, for example, by entering information in a voluntary online form, sending us an email, registering for a premium subscription, or by performing a premium service transaction using an assigned user ID and password. 

Here is how we handle information about your visit to our web site: 

**_
  * If you visit our site to browse through the web site, read pages, or download information:
_**___****_
    * If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the web site, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. Your web browser software transmits most of this information to us. This information does **not** identify you personally. 
    * We automatically collect and store **only** the following information about your visit:
      * The numeric IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access the _accessIndiana_ web site. Our software can then map these IP addresses into Internet domain names, for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain; 
      * The type of browser and operating system used to access the _accessIndiana_ web site; 
      * The date and time you access the _accessIndiana_ web site; 
      * The pages you visit, including graphics loaded from each page and other documents you download, such as PDF (Portable Document Format) files and word processing documents; and 
      * If you linked to the _accessIndiana_ web site from another web site, the address of that web site. Like No. 2 above, your web browser software transmits this information to us.
    * We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do **not** track or record information about individuals and their visits. 
**_
  * "Cookies"
_**___****_
    * A "cookie" is a small text file that a web site can place on your computer's hard drive in order, for example, to collect information about your activities on the site or to make it possible for you to use an online "shopping cart" to keep track of items you wish to purchase. The cookie transmits this information back to the Web site's computer which, generally speaking, is the only computer that can read it. Most consumers do not know that "cookies" are being placed on their computers when they visit web sites. If you want to know when this happens, or to prevent it from happening, you can set your browser to warn you when a web site attempts to place a "cookie" on your computer. 
    * We discourage the use of web cookies on our Web sites. Temporary cookies, however, may be used when necessary to complete a transaction. Certain services, such as Secretary of State services, use cookies to enhance the user experience and avoid multiple login/password authentication. If a persistent Web cookie is required, the Web page discloses to visitors that a persistent cookie is being used. Information collected on our Web sites including information from persistent Web cookies is generally subject to Indiana [Access to Public Records Law](http://www.ai.org/legislative/ic/code/title5/ar14/ch3.html) except as otherwise provided by Indiana or federal law.

**__
  * _If you choose to identify yourself by sending us an email or by using our online forms (for example,_ _Rapid Renewal of your automobile registrations, Professional Service Bureau volunteer applications, requests for site feedback)_ _:_
 __**__

_****_
    * _accessIndiana_ and the various state agencies it serves may ask for your e-mail address in order to process various applications available through _accessIndiana_ – for example, Rapid Renewal of your automobile registrations, Professional Service Bureau volunteer applications, requests for site feedback, surveys, and contests. 
    * When you use our Instant Access service and pay by credit card, we ask for the cardholder’s name, address, account number, and card expiration date. 
    * When you perform a transaction using a premium service, we will log the user’s login name for billing purposes or for other purposes required by law. In addition, as _accessIndiana_ grows, it may offer services such as a business or consumer portals or customization features, and will likely ask for your e-mail and other information. 
    * All of these activities are purely voluntary. You will always have the option of whether to perform the transaction and provide this information. Please understand, however, that in order to open a premium service account or perform a service transaction, you will be required to provide some personal information. Whether to perform the transaction is up to you.. 
    * If you choose to provide us with personal information -- as when you fill in an online registration for premium services, send an e-mail to site administrator, the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, or someone else, or by filling out some other form with your personal information and submitting it to us through our web site -- we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We treat e-mails the same way we treat letters sent to _accessIndiana_. 
    * We only share the information you give us with another government agency if your inquiry relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law. 
    * You may choose to subscribe to "Access Extra", our online newsletter describing new services and updates on the site. You may unsubscribe at any time.
    * Registered users can edit or delete their account information by e-mailing, phoning, or faxing _accessIndiana_. Please understand that, although we can delete your account online, state records retention laws may require us to maintain information about your account for a period of years. 
    * _accessIndiana_ does not collect information for commercial marketing. We will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone. 

**_
  * Indiana Public Records Act
_**__

_****_
    * We are required to maintain many documents under the [Indiana Access to Public Records Act](http://www.ai.org/legislative/ic/code/title5/ar14/ch3.html) for archive and historical purposes, but we do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you or for other purposes required by law. 
    * In certain circumstances, including requests from private individuals, or in accordance with Indiana public record statutes, we may be required to disclose the information you submit. If you use one of our online forms, the information you provide is up to you. If you don't provide your name or other information, it may be impossible for us to refer, respond to, or investigate your complaint or request. 
    * For more information on the Indiana Access to Public Records Act, click [here](http://www.ai.org/legislative/ic/code/title5/ar14/ch3.html), or visit the web page for the Indiana Public Access Counselor, by clicking [here](http://www.state.in.us/pac/). 

**
  * __accessIndiana_ will send personally identifiable information about you to other companies, agencies, or people when: _
__**__

_****_
    * We have your consent to share the information; 
    * We need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested. For example, we use a third party billing company, and we send information for billing purposes only; 
    * We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of _accessIndiana_ to provide a product or service to you. (Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us); 
    * We are required to do so by law, subpoena, court order or legal process; or
    * We find that your actions on our web sites violate the _accessIndiana_ Terms of Service or any of our usage guidelines for specific products or services. 

**_
  * Online Transactions With Governmental Agencies
_**__

_****_
    * When you provide personally identifiable information to state agencies through _accessIndiana_ in order to receive requested specialized services, such information is handled as it would be on an in-person visit to a government office, and subject to the laws, regulations, practices, and procedures of the respective agency.

**_
  * Personally Identifiable Information Available From Governmental Agencies Over the Web
_**__

_****_
    * Some governmental agencies may already have, or may acquire, personally identifiable information through the normal functions of government. Indiana law governs the use of this information – see the [Indiana Public Records Act](http://www.ai.org/legislative/ic/code/title5/ar14/ch3.html). If state or federal law treats information as public and not confidential, a state agency may choose to make the record available through _accessIndiana_ , in much the same manner as the agency would make a record available to a member of the public who visits the agency in person.

**_
  * Links to Other Sites
_**__

_****_
    * The _accessIndiana_ website contains links to many state agencies and other public sector resources. In a few cases, we link to private organizations ( _such as Mapquest and Yahoo!)_ , with their permission. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. 

**_
  * Security
_**__

_****_
    * We take very seriously the integrity of the information and systems that we maintain. As such, we have instituted security measures for all information systems under our control so that information will not be lost, misused or altered.
    * For site security purposes and to ensure that our Internet services remain available to all users, we employ software programs to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. In the event of authorized law enforcement investigations and pursuant to any required legal process, information from these sources may be used to help identify an individual.
    * Your _accessIndiana_ account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. In certain areas, as with credit card transactions, _accessIndiana_ uses industry-standard secure socket layer (SSL) encryption to protect data transmissions.
    * All credit card information is immediately encrypted upon receipt and authentication through CyberCash. CyberCash authentication uses 128-bit SSL communication.

**_
  * Kids' Page Safety and Privacy
_**__

_****_
    * _accessIndiana_ is not directed to children under 13, and does not knowingly collect personal information from children. For more information about children’s privacy generally, please see the Federal Trade Commission’s [Kidz Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html) web page.
_
    * We hope parents and teachers are involved in children's Internet explorations. It is particularly important for parents to guide their children when children are asked to provide personal information online.

 _accessIndiana_ does not sell products or services for purchase by children. If you are under 18, we specifically ask children to get their parents' permission before providing any information on line -- at our site or any other site -- and hope parents will always be involved in those decisions. Most importantly, in the event children do provide information through the _accessIndiana_ website, it is only used to enable us to respond to the writer, and not to create profiles of children. 

_
__

_
  * **Changes to this Privacy Policy**
 ****__****_
    * The [Enhanced Data Access Review Committee (EDARC)](http://www.state.in.us/legislative/ic/code/title5/ar21/ch6.html) has approved this policy. _accessIndiana_ may, with the approval of EDARC, revise this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our pages. This is a statement of policy and should not be interpreted as a contract of any kind. 

**_
  * More Information About Safe Surfing
_**__

_****_
    * Click [here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission. 

**_
  * Who Owns and Runs this Site?
_**__

_****_
    * This Site is owned by _accessIndiana_ ("AI"), an initiative of the [Intelenet Commission](http://www.state.in.us/intel/), a body corporate and politic of the State of Indiana pursuant to Ind. Code § 5-21 _et seq._ , on behalf of the Indiana state agencies appearing on the Site and state government administration.  Each agency is responsible for its respective website, public records, information and services provided through the Intelenet Commission's _accessIndiana_ service contract.  Additionally, the Site’s governing body, the Enhanced Data Access Review Committee, is constituted under the Intelenet Commission's Indiana Code (IC 5-21-6). 
    * Intelenet’s address is: Intelenet Commission, 101 West Ohio Street, Suite 800, Indianapolis, Indiana 46204-1974, 317-233-8990. 
    * The site is developed and maintained by Indiana Interactive, Inc., under contract with the Intelenet Commission. Please see "About _accessIndiana_."

**_
  * Contact Us:
_**__

_****_
    * We welcome your comments, questions or concerns. You may contact us at:

_accessIndiana_  
Privacy Coordinator  
C/o Intelenet Commission  
ATTN: Mr. Jerry Sullivan, Executive Director  
101 West Ohio Street, Suite 800  
Indianapolis, Indiana 46204  
email: [privacy@intelenet.state.in.us](mailto:privacy@intelenet.state.in.us)  
Telephone: 317-233-8990 Fax: 317-233-9000
